Vaibhav R. Chawade

Self-driven and motivated Certified Life Coach, Entrepreneur with a proven track record of success and remarkable achievements in building companies from the simple idea to sustainable expanding businesses. The proven positive impact on the individuals' personal & professional life through exceptional Simplified Teaching, Knowledge of Information Technology, Emotional Intelligence & Life Coaching philosophy.



vrchawade@yahoo.com, vaibhav.chawade@gmail.com



+91 9869123010/ +91 9821078258

Professional Skills

- Goal-oriented
- **Problem Solving**
- **Project Management** Skills
- Team Building & Leadership
- Risk Analysis & **Decision Making**
- **Business Development**
- & Management Effective
- Communication **Strategies**
- **Analytical Skills**
- Change Management
- People Management **Certified Life Coaching**
- ✓ Emotional Intelligence

Education

Master of Arts, **Emotional Intelligence** Life Coaching

First Class with Distinction CGPA 8.35 GICED University of Mumbai

(2020-2022)

Post Graduate Diploma in Business Management (PGDBM),

Systems

First Class, 67% Chetana's Institute of Management Studies & Research, Bandra (2005-2007)

Computer Engineering

Bachelor of Engineering

First Class, 62.2% Mumbai University-(2000-2004)

HSC,

First Class, 62% (1999-2000)

First Class, 74.26% (1997-1998)

Consulting Experience

Business Development & Management for Turnkey Projects

- Understood & analysed business requirements of clients and addressed the issues as the business case study
- Consulted preparation of business documents, implemented, controlled, and updated all aspects of the Project including Scheduling, Budgets, Buyout, Subcontractors, Permits, Safety Plan, Quality Plan, Communication Plan, Progress Reports, Meeting Minutes, Schedule of Values, Leading Owner Meetings, Leading Internal Meetings
- Managed risks on projects to assure completion on time and within budget & maintained customer satisfaction by investigating concerns, implementing corrective action, and communicating with customers and assigned staff
- Established professional relationships and communicated with field support staff, customers, and their representatives
- Start up and entrepreneurship coaching and mentoring.

Human Resource Management Project- Training, **Development** Recruitment

- Working with Padmashri Sindhutai Sapkal's NGO from past 6 years as a Psychology professional and digital marketing expert.
- · Identified training needs for the electrical domain as subject matter expert and other affiliated skills for the improvement of productivity
- Trained more than 2000 people in various business schools and, corporate houses on more than 32 technical and managerial subjects over the past 15 years.

Work Experience (Industrial)

Freelancer business consultant (3 Months) Nov 2023- Till date

Currently working as freelance consultant to FairEarth consultants LLP and SHP Solution Mumbai

Founder & Director (5 years)

FairEarth Consultants LLP

Responsibilities

Leading an impact-focused global technology consulting and services associated with GIS, IoT-based precision farming, and plant automation

March 2018- August 2022

- Liasoning, onboarding, and implementing projects related to sustainable (ecological) cities designed on the Electric Utilities & Smart Grid, Water Utilities & Sanitation, Smart Buildings & Communities, Disaster Management
- & Mitigation, E-Governance & Digitalization, Land Management & Reforms Addressing end-to-end business processes and providing solutions that span across the entire business value chain – from Consulting, Problem Definition, Requirement Analysis, Solutioning, Data Modeling, and Information Management to Analytics and Decision Support
- Mentor to many start-ups & young entrepreneurship group.

Founder & Technical Consultant (6 years)

Vampires Infosystems

August 2012- August 2018

Responsibilities

- Founded a software development company in August 2012 & led a team of 20 people associated with a GIS venture called Omkar Enterprises
- Associated with Disha Consultancy as Associate Director for the educational wing and SHP Solutions & Mango's Enterprises Mumbai as Technical consultant
- Successfully launched our dream project of site www.cashmybrain.com in September 2013 which is an earning and learning website.
- Directed the team in all the aspects of the business functions.

Behavioural Competency

- Innovative Approach
- Empathetic in nature & provide coaching by reading people's minds
- Keen observation of business planning & scalability
- Patience for gathering requirements & key points
- Relativity for resolving complexity
- Ability to communicate with various levels of mindsets for change management
- Visionary Leadership
- Result-oriented Approach
- Accommodate easily in the new environment & new people

Additional Qualifications

- Post Graduate Diploma in Digital Marketing and Metrics from S P Jain School of Global Management
- Completed MSc. Part-I in Psychotherapy & Counseling
- Diploma in Cyber Law from (Asian Institute of Cyber Law)

Personal Snippet

Date of Birth-March 20, 1983 Gender- Male Nationality- Indian Marital Status- Married Address-

104/8, Millennium Park, Hariom Nagar E. E Highway, Mulund (East), Mumbai- 400081

Business Analyst / Subject matter Expert (Electrical Domain) /Trainer/ Project Management Officer (2.5 years)

RMSI Pvt Ltd

Overview

RMSI Pvt. Ltd develops innovative solutions that integrate geographic information with niche business applications. RMSI is a CMMi level 5 assessed and ISO 9001:2000 certified company

IT & GIS implementation project for Rajasthan & Maharashtra State Electricity Board (Team Size: 20)

- Interacted with clients for requirement gathering and feasibility study
- Spearheaded documentation & technical support for application development
- Prepared the test cases and perform the testing on the application
- Trained stakeholders on the newly developed applications
- Developed & implemented process for AutoCAD to ArcFM data migration tools
- · Prepared process for network asset coding and consumer indexing
- Led project management activities for GIS data QA/QC for Rajasthan state & Maharashtra state RAPDRP
- Conducted reconciliation of project status and reported to various internal & external stakeholders (MIS)
- Assessed project forecasting and budget allocation for smooth project management
- Lead a team of MIS people, Trainers in the electrical domain
- Prepared new proposal/presentation creation for new projects & new business initiatives
- Successfully managed Data model changes and performed the impact assessment on various integrated modules

Assistant Manager (2.5 years)

Reliance Infrastructure LTD

June 2007- January 2010

February 2010- August 2012

Overview

Reliance Energy Limited (Reliance Infrastructure LTD) is a company with diversified businesses related to electricity like generation, distribution, transmission & some other businesses such as Infrastructure, Real estate, Road construction, Metro rail, etc.

Skills: ArcIMS, ArcGIS, Javascripts, JSP, XML, Team size: 6, Role: Business Analyst, Trainer

GIS websites for DAKC SEZ, Shahapur Power Plant, REL electrical network in Mumbai & Delhi, Mumbai Metro rail project first phase

• Implemented 'Responder' as Outage Management System in REL Mumbai with added GIS features to the "Complaint Management System"

Business Analyst Responsibilities-

- Project integration, scheduling & tracking
- Understanding & gathering user requirements
- Configuration & system integration management
- System installation and network management server configuration
- Database as well as data model handling
- Business analysis for SCADA-GIS integration for Outage management system (OMS)

Collaborative Industrial Work experience in SHP Solution (2012-2022)

 A newly formed organization that deals with GIS Survey/ Software development, currently doing some projects in Haryana, Maharashtra state in GIS (utility sector)

Responsibilities-

- Conducted feasibility study of various RFP documents.
- Engaged in preparation of technical & financial proposals
- Interacted with clients & identified new business opportunities

<u>Languages</u>

Hindi • • • •

Lectureship, Teaching and Coaching Experience (2004-2023)

IES's Management College and Research Centre (Aug 2022- Nov 2023) Full time

- As assistant professor subject teaching IT for management for PGDM first year students.
 - Administrative work:- Social media and digital marketing for institutional promotional activities. Branding and promotion activities as committee member. Sports in-charge for internal and external sports events.

K. J. Somaiya IEIT (2004-2005) Full time

- As lecturer the subjects taught are System Programming, Computer programming Object-oriented programming with C++
- As Examination Controller of Mumbai University: Administration of Mumbai University examinations

Shreeram Polytechnic, Airoli (2004) Full time

Subjects taught are Digital Techniques in Microprocessor, Information System Analysis & Design

Xavier's Institute of Technology, Mahim & Bharti Vidyapeeth's College of Engineering, Kharghar. (2013) Visiting

 Subjects taught: - "Management of Technology Innovations" for IVth semester Information technology

Chetana's Institute of Management and Research (2012-2022) Visiting

• Subject Taught: - MIS for second semester PGDM students

Chetana's RK institute of Management Study and Research (2012-2022) Visiting

 Subject Teaching: - Managing technology Business, DBMS, Data warehousing-Data mining & Technology Platforms for third semester MMS system specialization

PTVA's Institute of Management (2015-2022) Visiting

 Subjects taught: - E-commerce, Managing Technology Business, Enterprise Management Systems, Effective and Management Communication to MMS students

IES College of management and research, Bandra (2012-2020) Visiting

- Subjects taught: Artificial Intelligence, Operations Analytics, Technology Platforms, Database Management, IT Governances third semester MMS system specialization
- For MIM course: Networking and Communications (Semester IV), It Quality Assurance & It Systems Control and Audit, Business dynamics of IT industry (Semester V), Quality Assurance and Software Marketing, Technology Forecasting

Yadaorao Tasgaokar Institute of Management and Research (2014-2015)

 Subjects taught: - Software Engineering, IT Gov & Compliances third semester MMS system specialization

MMK college, Bandra (West) (2021-2022) Visiting

IT for business management, Computer skills

Quantum Education Center, Dombivli (2013-2017)

- Working as visiting faculty for TYBSc, and TYBSc IT students for the past four years
- Subjects Taught: System Software, Project Management, and Software Engineering